<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prakhar Saxena</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 11: Final Evaluation!</title>
        <description>
          
          During this week, I implemented all the remaining functions of Phase-3. These included plot_shear_stress(), max_shear_force(), max_bending_moment(), and max_deflection() functions. As this was the last week of GSoC, I also had to prepare a report stating all the work I did during summer. The report can be found here. plot_shear_stress() This...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-08-22-GSoCw11/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-08-22-GSoCw11/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 10: Phase 3 begins!</title>
        <description>
          
          During this week, I implemented the last part of Phase-2. These included solve_for_ild_moment() and plot_ild_moment() functions. The solve_for_ild_moment() function uses the solve_for_ild_reactions() function and calculates the I.L.D. equations for moment at a point specified by the user. The derived equations can then be plotted using the plot_ild_moment() function. solve_for_ild_moment() This...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-08-15-GSoCw10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-08-15-GSoCw10/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 9: Phase 2 continues!</title>
        <description>
          
          During this week, I implemented the solve_for_ild_shear() function. This function uses the solve_for_ild_reactions() function and calculates the I.L.D. equations for shear at a point specified by the user. The derived equations can then be plotted using the plot_ild_shear() function. solve_for_ild_shear() This function calculates the shear equations in terms of ‘x’....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-08-08-GSoCw9/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-08-08-GSoCw9/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 7 and 8: Back to Phase-2!</title>
        <description>
          
          These two weeks were spent on imploving the solve_for_ild_reactions() function and resolving the backwards incompatibility caused by the existing functions. After finding a decent solution, the functions were implemented and successfully merged. solve_for_ild_reactions() This function solves the reaction equations in terms of ‘x’. Here ‘x’ represents the distance of the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-08-01-GSoCw7n8/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-08-01-GSoCw7n8/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 6: First Evaluation!</title>
        <description>
          
          The first evaluation of GSoC occured this week and I am happy to announce that I have successfully passed it. The mentors also left an amazing feedback of my work. I.L.D. for reactions This week was spent on further refining the solve_for_ild_reactions() and plot_ild_reactions() to accomodate the changes suggested by...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-07-18-GSoCw6/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-07-18-GSoCw6/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 4 and 5: Phase-2 Begins!</title>
        <description>
          
          During the 4th week, I made some changes to the last PR of phase-1 and it got merged successfully. The rest of the week was spent researching on the topics of Phase-2. This involved going through some books and reading through research papers. Phase-2: Influence Line Diagrams In phase-2, I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-07-11-GSoCw4n5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-07-11-GSoCw4n5/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 3: Phase-1 over!</title>
        <description>
          
          During this week, I pushed the last function of phase-1, plot_loading_results(). This function displays all the graphs of the other functions on a single plot. After making some changes suggested by the mentors, the PR is ready to merge and phase-1 is finally over. plot_loading_results() This function was made similar...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-06-27-GSoCw3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-06-27-GSoCw3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 2: Merge Conficts!</title>
        <description>
          
          The second week of coding period ended. During this week, I simply implemented some minor changes suggested by the mentors. However, at the time of merging I faced a lot of merge conflicts as all my PRs made changes to the same file. After dealing with them, the PRs got...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-06-20-GSoCw2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-06-20-GSoCw2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Week 1: The grind begins!</title>
        <description>
          
          The community bonding period of GSoC ended recently and the official coding period has started from 7th June 2021. During the community bonding period, I got in touch with my mentors, Ishan Joshi and Nikhil Maan. All three of us share an engineering background and coincidently, live in the same...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-06-11-GSoCw1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-06-11-GSoCw1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Summer of Code 2021</title>
        <description>
          
          The results of GSoC 2021 were declared the previous week and I am really excited to announce that my proposal was accepted by SymPy. What is Google Summer of Code? I would simply put this as verbatim from Google’s site, ‘‘ Google Summer of Code is a global program focused...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-05-27-GSoC/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-05-27-GSoC/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
